<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>By the Major. Whereas by a precept of the 29. of August last, which was awarded in pursuance of an order of common-councell that day made, it was required that the collectors for the arrears of the assessments for the army under the command of Lord Fairfax...</title>
            <author>City of London (England). Lord Mayor.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1648</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A74111</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Thomason 669.f.13[11]</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">50811832</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 50811832</idno>
            <idno type="VID">162906</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A74111)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 162906)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Thomason Tracts ; 246:669f13[11])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>By the Major. Whereas by a precept of the 29. of August last, which was awarded in pursuance of an order of common-councell that day made, it was required that the collectors for the arrears of the assessments for the army under the command of Lord Fairfax...</title>
                  <author>City of London (England). Lord Mayor.</author>
                  <author>Warner, John, Sir, d. 1648.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by Richard Cotes Printer to the honorable city of London,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1648.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Dated at end: Guildhall London, this Fourth day of September, 1648.</note>
                  <note>Annotation on Thomason copy: "Sept ye 9".</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>England and Wales. --  Army --  Appropriations and expenditures --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>London (England) --  History --  17th century --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  Civil War, 1642-1649 --  Finance --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2008-06</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-09</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-08</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-08</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="letter">
            <pb facs="tcp:162906:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 1 -->
            <head>
               <figure>
                  <figDesc>blazon of the City of London</figDesc>
               </figure>
            </head>
            <head>By the Major.</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hereas by a Precept of the 29. of <hi>Auguſt</hi> laſt, which was awarded in purſuance of an Order of Common-councell that day made, it was required that the Collectors for the Arrears of the Aſſeſſments for the Army under the command of the Lord <hi>Fairfax,</hi> with the aſſiſtance of the Deputy and Common-councell-men of every Ward ſhould uſe their uttermoſt endevours for the Collecting of the ſaid Arrears, and upon Saturday laſt ſhould pay all moneys in their hands to the Treaſurers for that purpoſe; And that on this day return ſhould be made to the Grand Committee for the ſaid Arrears of the Names of all perſons that ſhould then owe any money upon the ſaid Aſſeſſments, and the ſummes ſo by them owing, in ſuch manner, and to ſuch purpoſe as in the ſaid Precept and Order is expreſſed: Now foraſmuch as the ſaid Deputies and Common-councell-men (as I am informed) did make relation to the ſaid Grand Committee of ſome proceedings upon the ſaid Precept towards the getting in of the ſaid Arrears; and that more would be done therein, if ſome further time were given, whereupon it was thought fit by the ſaid Grand Committee, That the ſaid Collectors, Deputies, and Common-councell-men ſhould have time untill Wedneſday the 13. of this preſent <hi>September,</hi> for the Collecting of the moneys ſo owing, and paying in of the moneys then remaining in the Collectors hands, and making the return of ſuch as ſhall not pay their Aſſeſſments: And for the doing of the other things thereby required to be done, with this intimation, that all perſons concerned therein, doe perform their duties accordingly, without expecta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of any further time of forbearance. Theſe are therefore once more to will and require the ſaid Collectors, with the aſsiſtance of the Deputy and Common-councell-men within their ſeverall Diviſions, to be very active and diligent in the Collecting of the ſaid ſeverall Aſſeſſments. And that the ſaid Collectors, on, or before Saturday next, do make up their Accompts concerning the ſame, with the ſaid Deputy and Common councell<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men, or ſome of them, and pay in the money then remaining in their hands to the Treaſurers as aforeſaid: And that the ſaid Deputy, Common-councell-men and Collectors doe make return to the ſaid Grand Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mittee on Wedneſday following of the Names of ſuch perſons within their Ward as have not paid their ſaid Aſſeſſments, and the ſummes by them owing, and the reaſons by them given why they doe not pay the ſame. And if any of the ſaid Collectors ſhall be remiſs and negligent in any of the ſaid particulars before-mentioned, or ſhall not doe their duties according to the ſeverall Ordinances of Parliament in that behalf; that then the ſaid Deputy and Common-councell-men ſhall return their Names to the ſaid Grand Committee, who according to an Order of the honourable Houſe of Commons, and ſpeciall directions of the Committee of that Houſe are to make return to the ſaid Committee of Parliament, not onely of the names of ſuch perſons as ſhall not pay their ſaid Arrears, but alſo of ſuch Collectors, Common-councell-men and others as ſhall fail in performance of their duties in this behalf to be further proceeded againſt as their neglect therein ſhall demerit. And there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore I require you to be carefull therein, not onely in regard of the preſent preſsing neceſsity for the money, but alſo for the preventing of further danger.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Dated at Guildhall London, <date>this Fourth day of September, 1648.</date>
               </dateline>
               <signed>Michel.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Printed by <hi>Richard Cotes</hi> Printer to the honorable City of <hi>London,</hi> 
               <date>1648. <add>Sept y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> 4</add>
               </date>
            </p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
